akari ga oreba kage ga dekiru to itta
You said if there's light, there are shadow
ano hi no kimi no koe ga wasure rarezu ni
I can't forget the words you said that day
tsuyoku aritai to negai
I wish to be strong
rousoku wo keshita yubi
I put out the candle with my finger
hi no watsusa ni inochi wo oboete
The heat of the flames reminded me of life
boku no koa ga hajikeru
The core of my being bursts open
guren no ai ga kokoro wo yaite
This red-hot love burns my heart
kaze ni mayoe ba namida ga ochiru
While wandering in the wind, tears start to fall
kizutsuki nagara mirai shinjite
Though I'm hurt, I believe in the future
mata saki e sono saki e
Let's go further and further ahead
gareki no sora wa bokura no kizuna
The rubble in the sky is our bond
osou mayakashi kechirashite yaru
I'll cut through the attempts to deceive me
tatakai no hate ni nani mo nakutemo
Even if there's nothing at the end of the battle
mata saki e sono saki e Ikou
Let's go further and further ahead
The Ties that Bind
（ナルト）忍連合の術だってばよ。
This is the Allied Shinobi Forces Jutsu!
（マダラ）哀れだな。
How pitiful.
（オビト）ああ。
Yeah.
やつらのすがっている希望など
存在しない。
This hope that they're all
clinging to doesn't exist.
今となっては　やつらの存在とて
それは　同じ。
Just like their very lives,
at this point.
（マダラ）十尾も頃合いのようだ。
It seems Ten Tails is ready.
（リー）第五杜門　開。
Fifth Gate of Closing! Open!
《十尾ではなく
今度こそ　俺たちが狙いか。
So this time, they're coming
after us, not Ten Tails...
まあ　敵の頭を叩くのは
基本だが…》
Well...
Taking the enemy's brains
is a fundamental strategy...
《作戦どおり　十尾の頭になってる
こいつらを倒す》
I'll follow the strategy and...
take down those two,
who are the brains of the Ten Tails!
《マダラ：それには　まず
十尾を止めないとな》
For that to work...
they would need to
stop the Ten Tails first!
（サクラ）うわっ。
うっ。
なぜだ　十尾とやらの動きは
止めたはず。
What?! I thought we had immobilized
the Ten Tails!
グハッ。
大丈夫か？　クソ。
Are you okay?! Damn it...
《肩の骨が外れやがったな》
My shoulder's dislocated...
見ろ　感知水球が。
Look at the Sensing Water Sphere...
これじゃ　まるで
１つの小さな星だ。
It's practically like a small planet.
こんなのは　ありえない。
But that's... impossible!
（シカク）十尾を
我々が止めたんじゃなく→
So we didn't immobilize
Ten Tails, after all?
あれが変化するために
力を溜めて→
It merely stopped moving on its own
動かなくなっただけだったのか。
in order to amass power
and undergo transformation?
（いのいち）こんなやつを
どうやって止める？
How are we going to be able to stop it?
２人を狙うどころではないぞ。
And now we can't target those two either!
（カカシ）それでも
あれを止めなければ→
But we have to stop that thing
or else it's over for us.
俺たちは　皆終わる。
（赤丸）クーン。
（キバ）チビリそうだぜ。
ウ～！
I'm about to pee myself...
（黄ツチ）ビビッてる暇があるなら
チャクラを練っておけ。
Instead of freaking out,
infuse your chakra!
本部からの作戦を受けて
すぐ動けるように準備しろ。
Be ready to move as soon as
we get the plan from HQ!
《シカク：十尾の動きを
止めるのは絶対だ。
We must immobilize Ten Tails...
でなければ　それを操る頭を
狙うことなど　できない。
or else we can't go after
the brains that are controlling it...
だが　どうやって止める？
But how?
止めるのが得意な
俺たち一族の術も→
Even with the jutsu of my clan
who specialize in immobilizing...
あれが相手では
チャクラを消費するわりに→
the effect would be miniscule compared
to the amount of chakra expended.
効果は　ほぼ…》
いのいち　カカシにつないでくれ。
おう。
Inoichi!
Link me to Kakashi!
Roger!
《シカク：カカシ　俺だ。
Kakashi, it's me!
さっき聞いた一連の戦闘の情報で
確かめたいことがある》
There's something
I want to confirm
regarding the intel from
the last battle sequence...
（マダラ）そろそろ十尾のコントロールが
難しくなってくる。
It's going to start getting more difficult
to control Ten Tails soon...
柱間細胞を使って
つながりを強くしておけ。
Reinforce your bond with it
using Hashirama's cells.
この状態の十尾が
どれほどの力か→
Don't you want to check out
Ten Tails' power in its current state?
確かめてみたくはないか？
まずは…。
First, let's...
ああ　やつらに
教えてやるのさ…。
Yes, let's show them...
絶望をな。
... despair!
《シカクさん　いったん切ります》
Shikaku, I'm going to
let you go for now!
《どうした？》
これは…。
What's the matter?!
（青）信じられん。
This is...
No way!
（青）シカク殿　いのいち殿。
Lord Shikaku! Lord Inoichi!
《ダメだ　神威じゃ間に合わない》
My Kamui won't make it in time!
土遁で足場を上へ。
おう。
Displace it upwards using
an Earth Style technique.
Right!
あんな距離まで…。
That far away?
前の尾獣たちと
比べものにならない。
It's so much greater than
all the previous Tailed Beasts!
なんて威力だ。
What power!
この程度でフラつくとは
コントロールが完全ではないな。
It's wobbly from just that little counter...
次だ。
Its control isn't perfect yet.
Next!
（ヒアシ）なんてことだ
あんな遠くの街が一瞬で。
Unbelievable! Such a far-off city
destroyed in an instant!
≪うわぁ～！
さっきからおかしいぞ。
遠くばかりを狙っているようだ。
It's been acting strange for a while,
it seems to be aiming far away!
（シカク）すべての街　人が
射程内ってことだ。
So all the cities,
and people are within its range of fire?
なら　避難した大名や
里を守っているみんな→
Then that means
the evacuated Feudal Lords,
everyone protecting the villages...
それに　国の人々も
安全じゃないってことか？
plus all the citizens of
each nation aren't safe?
戦場では　忍たちが　そのみんなを
守るために戦っている。
Our shinobi on the battlefield are
fighting to protect everyone else...
それを　なくそうというわけだ。
Those two are trying to eliminate
our reason for this war.
《ネジ：あの方向は…》
That's the direction of--!
（青）こ　これは…。
（いのいち）どうした？　青殿。
Th-This is...
What's wrong, Lord Ao?!
冷静に聞いてくれ。
Please listen to me calmly.
ここか…。
Here, eh?
シカク　どうする？
Well, Shikaku... What do we do?
やるべきことをやるだけだ。
Just keep doing what we must do.
最後の仕事だ。
戦場のみんなとつなげてくれ。
It will be our last act.
Put me through to
everyone on the battlefield.
十尾を止める策がある。
I have a plan to stop the Ten Tails!
（マダラ）やっと当たったな。
Finally got them.
これで連合の頭は潰した。
We've now smashed
the brains of the Allied Forces.
まっ　基本だな。
Like I said before,
it's fundamental strategy.
（チョウジ）シカマル…。
Shikamaru...
（シカマル）今は戦争中だ。
余計な言葉はいらねえ。
We're in the middle of a war.
Don't waste any words on me.
（シカマル）いのにもだ。
Or on Ino.
親父の言ったとおりに
やるだけだ。
Like Dad said, we just have
to do what we have to do.
これって
どういうことだってばよ！？
Wait... What exactly just happened?!
（ネジ）お前が　作戦のキーってことだ。
You are the key to our plan.
ちげえよ！　シカクといのいちの
おっちゃんたちは→
Not about that!
I'm asking what happened to
Shikaku and Inoichi?!
どうなったって聞いてんだ！
（忍たち）うわぁ～！
（ヒアシ）ネジ　お前は右回転だ！
わかった。
Neji! Rotate clockwise!
Got it!
（ネジ／ヒアシ）八卦掌回天！
- Eight Trigrams Palm Rotation!
す　すげえ！
A-Amazing...
ボケッとするな　ナルト。
ここは戦場で　今は戦闘中だ。
Don't just stand there
spacing out, Naruto!
This is a battlefield
and we're in a war.
人も死ぬ。
People will die!
（ヒアシ）だが　この戦いに敗れれば→
But if we are defeated
and lose this war...
すべての人が死ぬことになる。
everyone will die!
もちろん　わかってる。
Of course I know that!
シカマルといのの父親たちも→
Shikamaru and Ino's father
would likely say, that as shinobi,
子より先に逝けたことは
忍として本望だと言うだろう。
they're glad to have died
before their children.
俺の父がそうだったように。
Just as my father did.
作戦には　ナルト
お前の力が必要になってくる。
Naruto, your power is critical
to the plan.
作戦遂行まで　なんとしても。
So until we execute it...
（ヒナタ）ナルト君を守り抜く！
We must protect you, Naruto!
ヒナタ！
Hinata!
心せよ！　日向は木ノ葉にて最強！
Know this!
The Hyuga are the mightiest
among the Hidden Leaf!
（マダラ）などと　やつらが口上を
のたまう前に→
There he goes...
I was hoping to take them down
攻撃をしてやろうと思ったが→
before they started
with the speeches, but...
十尾をうまくコントロールできんな。
It's hard to control Ten Tails well.
この状態までは
これでいけるだろうが→
This ought to do until
the next transformation, but...
次こそは　人柱力にならねば
十尾をコントロールできんようだ。
Afterwards...
I suspect only a Jinchuriki will
be able to control it.
俺が十尾の人柱力になるには→
Though for me to become
the Ten Tails' Jinchuriki...
俺自身が
穢土転生の死体ではなく→
I'll need to be fully alive,
生命体になる必要があるのだがな。
not hosted within a corpse
as a Reanimation.
道連れがモットーの
穢土転生のあんたが→
Reanimations like you are perfect
for large-scale suicidal attacks.
この足もとの連合に自爆覚悟で→
But the reason
you haven't launched
the Ten Tails Tailed Beast Bomb
at them, blowing yourself up as well,
十尾の尾獣玉を
撃ち込まないのは→
その巻き添えで
俺まで死んでしまうからだ。
is because I'd get caught up
in it and die too.
そうなっては困る理由…。
And the reason that
would be a problem,
人柱力になるために　あんたが
本当の意味で生き返るには→
is because in order for you to
truly be brought back to life
and become a Jinchuriki...
俺があんたに輪廻転生の術を
命を捨ててするしかないからな。
you need me to sacrifice myself
and perform the Gedo Art of
Rinne Rebirth on you.
つまり　今のあんたは俺の
言うことを聞かざるをえない→
In short, you're in
a delicate position right now
where you're entirely at my mercy.
微妙な立場にある。　忘れるな。
Don't forget that.
あのジャリが　ずいぶんと
したたかになったものだ。
Well, well, that rug rat sure
has become the wily fox.
昔からべつに　あんたを
仲間だと思ったことはない。
I never considered you a friend.
フッ　それでいい。
Fine then.
なら　次にどうするか
お前が決めろ。
You decide our next move then.
続きだ。　絶望を教えてやるのさ。
丁寧にな。
We continue.
They will know despair... thoroughly.
（十尾）ギィ～ッ！
（オビト）木遁　挿し木の術！
Wood Style!
Cutting Sprigs!
うわっ！
There's so many of them!
Just try to evade them.
《九尾の力が戻るまで→
My Mountain Jutsu should
at least slow it down
わしの山土の術なら
少しは止められるはず。
until Nine Tails' strength returns.
しかし　チャクラを練る時間がかかる。
それまで…》
Except I need some time
to build up enough chakra!
Hold on, everybody!
（サクラ）しゃあ～んなろぉ～！
Shannaro!
《ネジ：なんて数だ。
回天が間に合わない》
So many!
My Rotation can't keep up!
クッ！
サンキュー　ネジ。
仙人モードになれたってばよ。
Thanks, Neji!
I can activate Sage Mode now!
天才ばかりに頼ってらんねえ。
こっから俺も…。
I can't keep relying on you geniuses!
Now it's my turn!
フン。
《螺旋手裏剣》
Rasen Shuriken!
おらぁ～！
まだまだ！
Here's a few more!
ハァ　ハァ…。
ハッ！
うわぁ！
八卦空壁掌。　はぁ～っ！
Eight Trigrams: Air Wall Palm!
《しまった。　ピンポイントか。
数が多すぎる。
Damn it! A focused attack!
There's too many!
ヒナタとネジの空掌では…》
（ネジ）白眼！
Hinata and Neji's Air Palms
won't be sufficient...
Byakugan!
《土遁　山土の術！》
Earth Style! Mountain Jutsu!
（黄ツチ）今だ！
（みんな）うぉ～！
医療班　どこだ？　重傷なんだ。
早く来てくれ！
Medical Team!
Where are you?!
There's a critical injury here!
Hurry!
いや　もう　俺は…。
No...
I'm no longer...
ネジ。
兄さん。
Neji...
Brother...
クッ…　ナルト。
Naruto...
ヒナタ様はお前のためなら死ぬ。
Lady Hinata...
is willing to die for you.
だから　お前の命は１つじゃない。
So... you hold more...
than one... life in your hands...
どうやら　俺の命も
その１つに入ってたようだ。
And it seems... that my life too...
may have been...
one of them....
なんで　お前はこんなとこで…。
Why? Why did you do this here?
お前は日向を…。
You were going to change
the Hyuga!
《かつてお前が　俺を運命の
呪縛から解放してくれた言葉》
Long ago, those words of yours,
freed me from the shackles of fate.
どうして俺にそこまで…。
Why would you go so far for me?
命をかけてまで　俺に。
Even give up your life...
お前に→
Because... you called me a genius...
天才だと言われたからだ。
((お前は俺と違って
落ちこぼれじゃねえんだから))
Unlike me, you're not a failure!
《父様　やっとわかったよ。
Father...
I finally understand...
the freedom you felt...
仲間を守るために死を選んだ
父様の自由の気持が》
choosing to die in order
to protect your comrades.
（オビト）仲間は殺させないんじゃ
なかったのか。　ナルト！
Didn't you say you wouldn't
let your friends die...?
Naruto!
((俺の仲間は絶対
殺させやしねえ！))
I'll never let my comrades die!
仲間は絶対殺させやしない
と言った　お前のその言葉。
Those words...
"I'll never let my comrades die."
さあ　辺りを見て
もう一度言ってみろ。
Now look around you...
and say it again!
もう一度言ってみろと
言っているんだ！
I told you to say it again!
冷たくなっていく
仲間に触れながら→
As the bodies of your comrades
grow cold in your arms...
実感しろ。　死を！
take in their deaths!
ネジが…　死んだ？
Neji's... dead?!
《ヒザシ　すまぬ…　ネジを》
Hizashi, forgive me...
I let Neji--!
これからこれが続く。
This will continue...
お前の軽い言葉も理念も
偽りになる。
And your flippant words and
ideology shall become lies.
理想や希望を語った結果がこれだ。
This is the end result of
hope and ideals.
これが現実なんだ。
This is reality!
ナルト…　この現実に何がある？
Naruto...
What is there for you in this reality?
父も母もいない。　師の自来也も。
Your mother and father are gone,
as well as your master, Jiraiya.
そして　お前が対立するかぎり→
And if you keep standing against us,
これから仲間も
そうやって次々いなくなる。
you'll continue to lose
your friends one by one.
お前を認める者が
存在しない世界だ。
This shall become a world
where no one who
acknowledges you will exist.
オビト。
Obito...
その先に待っているのは→
The only thing that awaits you...
is your worst nightmare,
which you know quite well!
お前もよく知る　最も恐ろしい…。
孤独だ。
Solitude!
《マダラ：まるでかつての
俺のようになったな　オビト。
You've become exactly
like the old me, Obito.
ナルトはもう少しで落ちる。
連合の心を折るか》
Naruto will give up shortly...
Which will break the will
of the Allied Forces.
現実にいる必要がどこにある？
Why must you cling to reality?
いいかげんこっちへ来い　ナルト。
Enough of this...
Now come join us, Naruto!
さっきネジ兄さんが言った→
Brother Neji just said,
ナルト君の命は一つじゃない
って意味…　わかる？
that you hold more than
one life in your hands.
Do you know what he meant?
仲間は絶対殺させない。
"I'll never let my comrades die."
その言葉も信念も偽りじゃない。
Neither those words nor
the conviction behind them are lies!
それを胸に
ちゃんとやってのけたの。
Because he was able to successfully
store them in his heart,
and live them out to until the end!
ネジ兄さんは。
Brother Neji did!
ナルト君だけじゃない…
みんながそうやって→
It's not just you, Naruto...
We all hold those words
and feelings in our hearts.
その言葉　想いと同じものを胸に
お互いに命をつなぎあってる。
They're what bind our lives together...
だから仲間なの。
and make us comrades.
その言葉と想いを　みんなが諦め
捨ててしまったら→
If we all give up and
discard those words and feelings,
ネジ兄さんのしたことも無駄になる。
Neji's final act will have been
for nothing.
それこそ本当に
仲間を殺すことになる。
And that is when...
your comrades truly die!
もう仲間じゃなくなってしまう
そう…　思うの。
For you are then
no longer comrades.
That's... how I feel.
だから　私と一緒に立とう　ナルト君。
So, stand with me, Naruto.
まっすぐ自分の言葉は曲げない。
私もそれが忍道だから！
Because never going back
on one's word...
is my Ninja Way too!
((ネジ：ナルト…
ヒナタ様は　お前のためなら死ぬ。
Naruto...
Lady Hinata...
is willing to die for you.
だから　お前の命は…。
So... you hold more...
（九喇嘛）１つじゃねえだろうが！
... than one life!
わしもいるの忘れるな！！
Don't forget about me!
わかってる
俺だってつながりは…。
I know.
I take my bonds seriously!
仲間は絶対捨てたかねえ！
でも　実際　ネジは…。
I'd never abandon my comrades!
But in reality, Neji is...
それ以上ぐだぐだ言ってみろ。
Stop your rambling!
ぶん殴って　今度こそ
お前の体をいただくぞ　コラ！
I'll beat you up and take over
your body for good this time!
これも忘れたのか！
And did you also forget?
てめえの父と母は
お前が生まれてすぐ→
Your mother and father did
the same thing Neji did
ネジと同じことをした。
just after you were born.
お前に敵であるわしまで封印し
未来を託して死んだ。
They sealed me,
their archenemy inside you,
and entrusted the future
to you and died.
てめえの命は
生まれたときからすでに→
Your life was already linked to
two others from the time you were born!
(２つの命でつながれてんだよ！))
動かずナルトの出方をうかがうか…。
Will he just stand back and
see how Naruto responds...?
ずいぶんと気になるようだな。
It seems Naruto makes him uneasy.
もういい！
Enough!
焦るな！
Don't be hasty!
それでは十尾が傷つくうえ
お前も…。
You're going to harm yourself
as well as Ten Tails!
少々　かまわん
十尾の表皮は強い！
I don't care!
Ten Tails hide is tough!
ここを狙う気だ！
They're going to hit us!
（キラービー）充電十分！
Recharging completed!
《オモイ：気をつけて　ビー様！》
Be careful, Lord Bee!
（カルイ）行っけぇ！！
Go get 'em!
これでも食らえ！
Take this!
（カルイ）ビー様！
（オモイ）無茶しないでください。
Lord Bee!
Don't go overboard!
心配無用
連合を守る俺なりの苦労。
There's no need to worry...
Protecting the Alliance is my territory!
《そうだ…　父ちゃんと
母ちゃんだけじゃねえ。
That's right.
It wasn't just Mom and Dad.
そうだろ…　今までだって。
Yeah...
It hasn't just been my life...
俺の命は　１つじゃねえ》
up until now.
ヒナタ　ありがとう。
Thanks, Hinata!
お前が
俺の横にいてくれたおかげだ！
It's all thanks to you
standing by my side.
《そして　ネジ…
ありがとだってばよ》
And Neji...
Thank you.
《ヒナタ：ナルト君の手って
大きくて　強くて　何より…》
Naruto's hand is so big...
and strong, but most of all...
行くぞ　ヒナタ！
うん！
Let's do this, Hinata!
Yeah!
《ヒナタ：とっても安心する》
It's comforting!
kidzuite ndaro sou sekai ga kataru itsuwari to
I'm sure you've realized by now that the world tells lies
amai wana ni soko ni wa hontou nante nai koto o
And lays alluring traps, but there's no truth behind them
riyuu sagashite run away why? sono mewotojiteru no?
Search for a reason Run away Why?
Why are you closing your eyes?
tell me why can't you
Tell me why can't you
shinjitsu ni te o nobase!
Reach out for the truth!
always (sakebe shout out) all time (tsukame catch up)
Always (Scream, Shout out)
All the time (Catch it, Catch up)
everybody knows (we are the seeker get fire!!!)
Everybody knows (We are the seeker Get fire!!!)
moyase moyase kokoro no honou
Burn, burn the fire in your heart
tsuyoku aritai to negau nonaraba
if you firmly wish for it
narase narase mezame no kane o
Ring, ring the bell of awakening
koyoi tsuki no shita de kokoro sakebe
Shout from your heart under the moon tonight
utae utae hoero hoero
Sing, sing, howl, howl,
kibou no hikari o nozomu nonaraba
if you want the light of hope
moyase moyase kokoro no honou
Burn, burn the fire in your heart
akai tsuki no shita de kimi o sakebe
Shout to you under the red moon
ima ima ima flame up (catch the fire)
Now, now, now, Flame up (Catch the fire)
ima ima ima flame up (blaze up!!!)
Now, now, now, Flame up (Blaze up!!!)
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
I haven't been able to save
many comrades...
美空ひばりです。
An existence where one can only
await one's death inside a cage...
It's a nice analogy.
では　最後まで
ごゆっくり　お楽しみください。
You're all exactly like that brat who
just died a pointless death.
Neji's will isn't dead yet!
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！にっぽんの歌』。
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華な歌手の
皆さんによる→
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Those Who Dance in the Shadows."